<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economy on Joseph Clift</title>
    <link>https://josephclift.com/tags/economy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economy on Joseph Clift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://josephclift.com/tags/economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from a crisis</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/lessons-from-a-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/lessons-from-a-crisis/</guid>
      <description>“What we are seeing today is a backwash from what happened 10 years ago.”
So claimed former Chancellor of the Exchequer, Alistair Darling, in an event organised by the RSA and held in London a couple of months ago. Darling was in charge of the nation’s finances when the biggest financial crisis in a generation hit in 2007. He articulated a view that has been forming with the recent political ructions and rise of populism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peggy and Mihaela</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/peggy-and-mihaela/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/peggy-and-mihaela/</guid>
      <description>I met Peggy first. We fell into step, two Brits abroad, dragging our carry-on luggage across the orbital road of Nice airport, walking to the hotel we had been sent to by our airline.
Our evening flight had been delayed, and they’d finally given up for the night. We’d be on the first flight to Heathrow the next morning. An air traffic control failure in Brussels caused the original problem. Appropriately timed: it was June 24th, the night following the Brexit vote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advertising&#39;s economic impact</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/advertising-economic-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/advertising-economic-impact/</guid>
      <description>Following a winter of what seemed like unbroken rain, there&amp;rsquo;s been a hint of spring in the air these past couple of weeks here in the UK. And the nicer weather&amp;rsquo;s been matched by increased optimism among both British economic and advertising forecasters. Official predictions for 2014 UK GDP growth were revised up to +2.7% earlier this week, suggesting that the economy will at last regain its pre-financial crisis peak this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can ads do good?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/can-ads-do-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/can-ads-do-good/</guid>
      <description>Some may deride this idea as corporate greenwashing, but the idea of brands &amp;ldquo;doing good&amp;rdquo; as well as making a profit is becoming an increasingly hot topic. I was struck earlier this month at the World Federation of Advertisers (WFA) conference by client after client highlighting the need for brands to have a social &amp;ldquo;purpose&amp;rdquo;.
With that in mind, today&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;doing good makes for good advertising&amp;rdquo; panel at Advertising Week Europe was very much on trend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling the Pinch: An update on the UK consumer</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/feeling-pinch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/feeling-pinch/</guid>
      <description>In these times of economic volatility, rising unemployment and fears of a double-dip recession, gauging consumer attitudes towards financial matters has become ever more important to both governments and businesses. In the UK, The Futures Company has been conducting an ongoing research project on the topic since 2008, entitled Feeling the Pinch. And its latest results, discussed at a briefing in London earlier this week, make for pretty depressing reading.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
