<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cities on Joseph Clift</title>
    <link>https://josephclift.com/tags/cities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cities on Joseph Clift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://josephclift.com/tags/cities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Who is Diamond Geezer?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/diamond-geezer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/diamond-geezer/</guid>
      <description>I was interested to see that Diamond Geezer, one of the best bloggers to have ever blogged, celebrated his twentieth blogiversary the other day. Despite me reading more of his work than any other author I can think of in terms of word count at least, I really don’t have a clue who he is.
This apex predator of Blogspot publishes around 1,100 words per day, up from around 600 a day in the early years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss Naysmith and her city</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/miss-naysmith/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/miss-naysmith/</guid>
      <description>The homeless have always featured in the stories Londoners tell. From doomed Jo in Bleak House, to John Healy’s mid-century memoir The Grass Arena, to the early 70s cult BBC TV movie Edna The Inebriate Woman, the city’s vagrants have worried and perplexed their more fortunate fellow citizens.
Most recently, Alan Bennett’s 1999 play The Lady In The Van, which told the story of the playwright’s 15-year friendship with a homeless woman – a Miss Shepherd – who moved into a van in his Primrose Hill garden, has been adapted for a “cosily enjoyable” movie released this winter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War on two wheels</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/war-on-two-wheels/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/war-on-two-wheels/</guid>
      <description>It was a normal winter&amp;rsquo;s evening on London&amp;rsquo;s worst street. Just out of the office, I walked towards Oxford Circus, up from the Centre Point end, where the tourist tat shops selling Union Jack keyrings, hoodies and wheelie suitcases give way to the fast-fashion chain stores. I began to cross the road, around the point I’d crossed hundreds of times before, on hundreds of previous commutes home.
A sudden charge in the atmosphere: a bike and a car were approaching, and the car was accelerating quite a bit, right behind the bike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another London</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/another-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/another-london/</guid>
      <description>Another London: looking up Tottenham Court Road, 1974.
The city at its grimiest (and emptiest). Note the wonky railings and hump in the pavement on the near side, and the pedestrian crossing to nowhere on the other side. And the strip of single-story lean-tos, rapid rebuilds after the previous buildings were bombed out in the war; they lasted all the way to the mid-90s, apparently.
Another country: the &amp;ldquo;three-day week&amp;rdquo; and petrol rationing had bitten in earlier in the year; the Common Market referendum was a year away; the IMF bailout came in 1976.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
