<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Joseph Clift</title>
    <link>https://josephclift.com/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Joseph Clift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://josephclift.com/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>11 gallery entrances in Paris</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/gallery-entrances/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/gallery-entrances/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been lucky during this pandemic. I have kept my job, and can work from home, which is safely isolated and peaceful. No close friends or family have caught the virus, symptomatically at least. All of this can change, of course. I pray it doesn’t.
But, four months in, all I can complain about is a cancelled trip to Paris, originally planned for March. Big wow.
My main hobby is visual art (see side project here), so gallery-going is the main focus of my Paris trips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google and the disappearing stars</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/google-disappearing-stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/google-disappearing-stars/</guid>
      <description>What’s the value exchange between me and Google?
Not to sound pompous, but this is one of the governing questions of my online life. But I didn’t give it a second thought until I noticed a few disappearing yellow stars.
Do you know about the cult of the stars, flags and hearts? For initiates, it’s one of the most useful bits of one of Google’s most useful apps. Which is kind of like saying one of the most lofty crags on Everest or hottest spots on the sun, considering the Mountain View-based tech behemoth’s terrifyingly high standards of utility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking somewhere</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/walking-somewhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/walking-somewhere/</guid>
      <description>I’d arrived in Trieste on a Friday evening, and, having dropped my backpack off, I needed to walk. So I set off, towards the sea.
Despite being a Friday, there was almost nobody about. The large, square Hapsburg buildings loomed for block after block at each intersection.
Trieste had been the Austro-Hungarian empire’s biggest seaport, a place of huge grandeur and wealth. Then, one imperial power had been replaced by another: Italian troops marched in at the end of the First World War, and had never left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cat guardians</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/cat-guardians/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/cat-guardians/</guid>
      <description>The beginning of the end of my 2016 came when I spent three days in Athens, alone. I went to the city with barely any preparation, beyond half-remembered Greek myths at school, an almost totally forgotten Homer course at university, a scrawled sheet of phrases (‘mee-LA-tay ag-lee-KA’?) and a cut-price air ticket for a midweek, mid-December getaway.
This lack of preparation turned out to be a good idea. Because everything came as a surprise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
