<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Joseph Clift</title>
    <link>https://josephclift.com/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Joseph Clift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://josephclift.com/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Agile glossary</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/an-agile-glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/an-agile-glossary/</guid>
      <description>This week, I got PMI-ACP certified, which involved taking and passing an exam. In the past couple of months, I put together this Agile glossary as a study aid. It’s an A-Z of Agile concepts, frameworks… and buzzwords. The information is based heavily on the study guide and online learning path I used. I hope it helps others studying for the exam, or can maybe be used as a more general reference tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epic documentation</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/epic-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/epic-documentation/</guid>
      <description>It’s right there in the Agile Manifesto: today’s product teams should prioritise “working software over comprehensive documentation”.
A nice thought. But having notched up several years of working with Agile teams, I feel like these five words have led to an unfortunate belief taking hold among certain zealots: that we don’t need documentation at all!
Which is nonsense. We need the leanest, briefest, most maintainable documentation possible. But we need documentation all the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google and the disappearing stars</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/google-disappearing-stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/google-disappearing-stars/</guid>
      <description>What’s the value exchange between me and Google?
Not to sound pompous, but this is one of the governing questions of my online life. But I didn’t give it a second thought until I noticed a few disappearing yellow stars.
Do you know about the cult of the stars, flags and hearts? For initiates, it’s one of the most useful bits of one of Google’s most useful apps. Which is kind of like saying one of the most lofty crags on Everest or hottest spots on the sun, considering the Mountain View-based tech behemoth’s terrifyingly high standards of utility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The four types of agency-client relationships</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/four-types-of-agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/four-types-of-agency/</guid>
      <description>Agency/client relationships are getting ever more fraught these days: you only had to look at this week’s announcement from WPP that its sales are taking a big whack, and ominous signals from big advertisers like P&amp;amp;G that they wish to “reinvent” their agency relationships – which will, safe to say, involve paying them a lot less.
If such relationships are getting a bit abusive these days, then, Anselmo Ramos, founder of the WPP-owned, Ogilvy-affiliated agency DAVID, is here to help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the purpose of brand purpose?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/whats-the-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/whats-the-purpose/</guid>
      <description>With so many heart-warming, CSR-led ads winning awards these days, setting a purpose seems to have become almost a prerequisite for launching a big brand campaign.
But many in adland would say these wins are due more to tugging on judges’ heartstrings rather than demonstrating great creativity or solid business results. Or even a sensible purpose in the first place!
This debate came into sharp focus at the Cannes Lions this year, according to a new analysis released by WARC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes we Kanban!</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/yes-we-kanban/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/yes-we-kanban/</guid>
      <description>Kanban is one of the most talked-about, but least-understood, ways we have of managing digital product development. At least, that’s the impression I got from a recent talk given by David Lowe, a Kanban expert and Scrum coach, at General Assembly in London.
A quick Google search suggests that Kanban has something to do with improving production processes in Japanese car factories. But a look around the blogosphere shows it’s since been sucked into the Agile/Scrum/Lean vortex that powers so much product discussion these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Management and Leadership</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/management-and-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/management-and-leadership/</guid>
      <description>Management is doing things right; leadership is doing the right things.
– Peter F. Drucker</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas: British Adland’s Super Bowl</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/christmas-adland-superbowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/christmas-adland-superbowl/</guid>
      <description>Last month, I had the chance to interview planning superbrains Toby Harrison and Les Binet of adam&amp;amp;eveDDB.
That’s the agency responsible for Christmas ad hits from this subversive online-only spot for bag brand Mulberry…
To the ongoing series of sentimental, lushly-produced spots for John Lewis: a rare example of an ad that becomes part of the national conversation.
“It feels like Christmas advertising is where it’s hot now,” Binet said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A pricing primer</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/a-pricing-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/a-pricing-primer/</guid>
      <description>Getting pricing right is a pretty fraught issue for brand owners. But what should the responsible marketer be doing to make things easier? The Psychology of Price, creative agency Draftfcb&amp;rsquo;s latest Breakfast Club event, held in London this morning, aimed to offer some answers. Behavioural economist Leigh Caldwell, author of a book of the same title as the briefing, and Draftfcb&amp;rsquo;s head of retail Niki Cook both offered their views – and both agreed that price-related decisions go a lot deeper than the actual costs of goods and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is advertising a science or an art?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/advertising-science-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/advertising-science-art/</guid>
      <description>Or, to put it another way, is advertising success achieved through incremental research, careful checking of data and sound planning – or is it more to do with the creative &amp;ldquo;eureka moment&amp;rdquo;? This &amp;ldquo;science vs art&amp;rdquo; question has troubled advertising&amp;rsquo;s biggest brains for decades. Remember that famous Bill Bernbach quote? &amp;ldquo;Advertising is fundamentally persuasion and persuasion happens to be not a science, but an art.&amp;rdquo;
The industry&amp;rsquo;s latest attempt at settling the matter came with a lively debate at the Edinburgh International Marketing Festival earlier this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nadia Comaneci&#39;s Olympic campaign</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/nadia-comaneci-olympic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/nadia-comaneci-olympic/</guid>
      <description>Many attendees of the annual Cannes Lions International Festival of Creativity pride themselves on being forward thinking. But at this year&amp;rsquo;s event, a lot of minds will be focused on one future date in particular: 27 July 2012, when the summer Olympic Games begin in London. If you want to know why this is, follow the money.
The Olympics are a prime cause of the industry&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;quadrennial effect&amp;rdquo; – the lift given to global adspend every four years due to the happy convergence of major summer sporting events and the US presidential election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why brand relevance explains market movements</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/brand-relevance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/brand-relevance/</guid>
      <description>Some brands make it big; most do not. But why are certain brands successful in the first place? And why does a still-smaller group of brands remain popular over the long term?
In his 2010 book Brand Relevance: Making Competitors Irrelevant, US academic David A. Aaker attempts to answer these questions. He claims that &amp;ldquo;relevance&amp;rdquo; is a crucial factor in a brand attaining market leadership - and that companies become relevant by creating their own category or subcategory through innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-opportunity: Making a slightly better world</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/writing/co-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/writing/co-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>John Grant discussed the concept of Co-opportunity - also the title of his latest book, see Warc summary here - with a packed audience of planners at an APG event in London yesterday.
The rise of social media has led to a dramatic shift in power towards consumers and away from brands (and marketers). Grant, a co-founder of St Luke&amp;rsquo;s, sees this process as beneficial rather than destructive. He argues that co-operation can benefit both brands&amp;rsquo; bottom lines and society as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
