<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Art on Joseph Clift</title>
    <link>https://josephclift.com/tags/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Art on Joseph Clift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://josephclift.com/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>11 gallery entrances in Paris</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/gallery-entrances/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/gallery-entrances/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been lucky during this pandemic. I have kept my job, and can work from home, which is safely isolated and peaceful. No close friends or family have caught the virus, symptomatically at least. All of this can change, of course. I pray it doesn’t.
But, four months in, all I can complain about is a cancelled trip to Paris, originally planned for March. Big wow.
My main hobby is visual art (see side project here), so gallery-going is the main focus of my Paris trips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I’m getting Artangled</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/why-im-getting-artangled/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/why-im-getting-artangled/</guid>
      <description>I went to a lot of art shows in 2017. I don’t really know why this obsession took hold.
It’s definitely an obsession by now though. My weird compulsion to track and quantify my cultural consumption – by making searchable notes about each show attended, film watched and book read on a Google Sheet – proves it.
My inability to set time aside for reading books hasn’t changed: according to the spreadsheet, in 2017, I read frankly pathetic 22 titles, most of which were trashy non-fiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The White Bottle</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/the-white-bottle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/the-white-bottle/</guid>
      <description>The painter Giorgio Morandi lived at 36 via Fondazza, in a quiet corner of Bologna. Morandi, a painter of calming yet weirdly intense still lives, had a reputation for obscurity, separation, reclusiveness. But the address is world famous: so much so that it’s been converted into a museum, open to the public for a couple of hours a week.
Three rooms in the apartment are glassed off, preserved as they were when the artist lived.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
