<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on Joseph Clift</title>
    <link>https://josephclift.com/tags/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on Joseph Clift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://josephclift.com/tags/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Not-so-hot coral</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/not-so-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/not-so-hot/</guid>
      <description>It’s always a pain when an ad isn’t worthy of what’s being advertised. Which is why seeing this spot from Monzo the other day felt like a particularly hard kick to the stomach.
Here’s why I’m about to be highly dramatic and over-critical about a tiny poster on a train. Monzo is the bank that has basically changed my life since switched my main current account there last year, due to its extreme convenience - all in the app!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google and the disappearing stars</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/google-disappearing-stars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/google-disappearing-stars/</guid>
      <description>What’s the value exchange between me and Google?
Not to sound pompous, but this is one of the governing questions of my online life. But I didn’t give it a second thought until I noticed a few disappearing yellow stars.
Do you know about the cult of the stars, flags and hearts? For initiates, it’s one of the most useful bits of one of Google’s most useful apps. Which is kind of like saying one of the most lofty crags on Everest or hottest spots on the sun, considering the Mountain View-based tech behemoth’s terrifyingly high standards of utility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop being a Product Martyr!</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/product-martyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/product-martyr/</guid>
      <description>“Being a product manager means that you have a lot of responsibility, but no authority.”
This simple statement has the ring of truth to me. I found it in Matt LeMay’s really useful book, ‘Product Management Fundamentals‘. Here’s how I feel about the responsibility/authority divide.
A good product manager multitasks a lot. And feels stretched. You tend to feel like a “jack of all trades, master of none”. And no wonder, because you spend so much of your time talking to people a lot more expert than you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing&#39;s Big Lie</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/marketings-big-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/marketings-big-lie/</guid>
      <description>Ever get suspicious that your Facebook friends are having too much fun? That the lives of people you follow on Instagram are too fabulous to be believed? According to Christophe Jouan, CEO of Future Foundation, all of this social media-based bragging should be a crucial concern for the marketing industry. Jouan talked to me about what he terms the Big Lie of marketing – also the title of a new book from Future Foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad tips from Facebook and YouTube</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/ad-tips-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/ad-tips-facebook/</guid>
      <description>Facebook has had one of the roughest months in its short history since becoming a public company, with lowlights ranging from a 16% decline in its stock price to media complaints about Mark Zuckerberg&amp;rsquo;s restaurant tipping habits. And things seemed to be going from bad to worse at the Cannes Lions International Festival of Creativity yesterday when Paul Adams, the firm&amp;rsquo;s global head of brand design, disappeared backstage soon after starting his keynote due to what seemed to be a bad case of stagefright.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
