<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Joseph Clift</title>
    <link>https://josephclift.com/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Joseph Clift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://josephclift.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Who is Diamond Geezer?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/diamond-geezer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/diamond-geezer/</guid>
      <description>I was interested to see that Diamond Geezer, one of the best bloggers to have ever blogged, celebrated his twentieth blogiversary the other day. Despite me reading more of his work than any other author I can think of in terms of word count at least, I really don’t have a clue who he is.
This apex predator of Blogspot publishes around 1,100 words per day, up from around 600 a day in the early years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four steps to clean cleaning</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/clean-cleaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/clean-cleaning/</guid>
      <description>I made some changes to the way I clean my flat a couple of months ago: scaling back on the number of products I use, mixing my own cleaners from bulk-bought ingredients, and buying most of the rest from an enlightened manufacturer I want to support. My flat’s as clean as before, I&amp;rsquo;ve reduced the environmental impact of my cleaning and I’ll save money over the long term.
While some of the new products and techniques were more successful than others, overall I haven’t looked back from making the change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSM1... and done</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/psm1-and-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/psm1-and-done/</guid>
      <description>So it’s done. After several weeks of reading a 19-page PDF file over and over, taking practice tests and reading countless blog posts, you can now, officially, call me master. Scrum Master. I got certified!
I’d have thought that would have come from the day job, where I work on two Scrum teams, but studying for the PSM1 Scrum Master certification actually underlined how little I knew about the guidelines of this process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 gallery entrances in Paris</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/gallery-entrances/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/gallery-entrances/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been lucky during this pandemic. I have kept my job, and can work from home, which is safely isolated and peaceful. No close friends or family have caught the virus, symptomatically at least. All of this can change, of course. I pray it doesn’t.
But, four months in, all I can complain about is a cancelled trip to Paris, originally planned for March. Big wow.
My main hobby is visual art (see side project here), so gallery-going is the main focus of my Paris trips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from a march</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/notes-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/notes-march/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled on today’s People’s Vote march by accident. Totally done in by the endless Brexit news cycle, having pinwheeled over the months and years since the referendum between hope and disillusionment, I’ve recently taken the coward’s way out: avoiding Twitter updates and news in general on the topic.
This meant that I vaguely knew about today’s parliamentary vote and the march, but this vagueness was sufficient for me to plan a Saturday afternoon trip to some West End galleries, which involved getting out at Green Park station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swimming at the Elephant</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/swimming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/swimming/</guid>
      <description>Feeling deadline-induced stress, along with the vague sense that you don’t do enough with your evenings that doesn&amp;rsquo;t involve said stress? I did, until I started weekly sessions at Out to Swim, an LGBT+ swimming club with classes in London and Brighton.
I hadn’t swum for 20 years before joining the club a few months back. Now, I leave a brightly-lit council-run pool in Elephant and Castle each Wednesday night with a definite spring in my step, the day’s worries forgotten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 life lessons from Amanda Lepore</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/lepore-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/lepore-life/</guid>
      <description>I wish I were Amanda Lepore - as Drag Race season 4 winner Sharon Needles sang that one time .
Anyone who sees I Hate New York - showing as part of Fringe at 3.30pm on Sunday 18 November - might find themselves wishing the same.
Gustavo Sánchez’s documentary, shot over a 10 year period, tells the story of Amanda, her ex-club kid frenemies Sophia Lamar, Chloe Dzubilo and T De Long - and the city they live in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>132 Days of Duolingo</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/132-days-of-duolingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/132-days-of-duolingo/</guid>
      <description>I spend around 10 minutes a day on Duolingo and I’m not convinced it’s worth it.
And the fact these doubts only started occurring to me after I completed a 100 day streak on this maddeningly well-designed and moreish app is… annoying.
Admittedly, 10 minutes a day isn’t a massive time commitment. But, over 100 days, that equals almost 17 hours. Most of a day! Is it even time well spent?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I’m getting Artangled</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/why-im-getting-artangled/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/why-im-getting-artangled/</guid>
      <description>I went to a lot of art shows in 2017. I don’t really know why this obsession took hold.
It’s definitely an obsession by now though. My weird compulsion to track and quantify my cultural consumption – by making searchable notes about each show attended, film watched and book read on a Google Sheet – proves it.
My inability to set time aside for reading books hasn’t changed: according to the spreadsheet, in 2017, I read frankly pathetic 22 titles, most of which were trashy non-fiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss Naysmith and her city</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/miss-naysmith/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/miss-naysmith/</guid>
      <description>The homeless have always featured in the stories Londoners tell. From doomed Jo in Bleak House, to John Healy’s mid-century memoir The Grass Arena, to the early 70s cult BBC TV movie Edna The Inebriate Woman, the city’s vagrants have worried and perplexed their more fortunate fellow citizens.
Most recently, Alan Bennett’s 1999 play The Lady In The Van, which told the story of the playwright’s 15-year friendship with a homeless woman – a Miss Shepherd – who moved into a van in his Primrose Hill garden, has been adapted for a “cosily enjoyable” movie released this winter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking somewhere</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/walking-somewhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/walking-somewhere/</guid>
      <description>I’d arrived in Trieste on a Friday evening, and, having dropped my backpack off, I needed to walk. So I set off, towards the sea.
Despite being a Friday, there was almost nobody about. The large, square Hapsburg buildings loomed for block after block at each intersection.
Trieste had been the Austro-Hungarian empire’s biggest seaport, a place of huge grandeur and wealth. Then, one imperial power had been replaced by another: Italian troops marched in at the end of the First World War, and had never left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cat guardians</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/cat-guardians/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/cat-guardians/</guid>
      <description>The beginning of the end of my 2016 came when I spent three days in Athens, alone. I went to the city with barely any preparation, beyond half-remembered Greek myths at school, an almost totally forgotten Homer course at university, a scrawled sheet of phrases (‘mee-LA-tay ag-lee-KA’?) and a cut-price air ticket for a midweek, mid-December getaway.
This lack of preparation turned out to be a good idea. Because everything came as a surprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peggy and Mihaela</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/peggy-and-mihaela/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/peggy-and-mihaela/</guid>
      <description>I met Peggy first. We fell into step, two Brits abroad, dragging our carry-on luggage across the orbital road of Nice airport, walking to the hotel we had been sent to by our airline.
Our evening flight had been delayed, and they’d finally given up for the night. We’d be on the first flight to Heathrow the next morning. An air traffic control failure in Brussels caused the original problem. Appropriately timed: it was June 24th, the night following the Brexit vote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War on two wheels</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/war-on-two-wheels/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/war-on-two-wheels/</guid>
      <description>It was a normal winter&amp;rsquo;s evening on London&amp;rsquo;s worst street. Just out of the office, I walked towards Oxford Circus, up from the Centre Point end, where the tourist tat shops selling Union Jack keyrings, hoodies and wheelie suitcases give way to the fast-fashion chain stores. I began to cross the road, around the point I’d crossed hundreds of times before, on hundreds of previous commutes home.
A sudden charge in the atmosphere: a bike and a car were approaching, and the car was accelerating quite a bit, right behind the bike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tapping the Kangaroo</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/tapping-the-kangaroo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/tapping-the-kangaroo/</guid>
      <description>Every day in London, thousands of fingers tap a cute Kangaroo logo on their smartphone screens. As a result, every lunchtime and supper time, thousands of young men have a job to do.
They’re participating in a new, digitally-enabled form of freelance labour: working for Deliveroo, the city’s number one takeaway app. Their job is to deliver food, on motorbikes and push bikes, toting huge, insulated square food-storage backpacks, branded with Deliveroo’s turquoise and black corporate colours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Chinese plate</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/the-chinese-plate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/the-chinese-plate/</guid>
      <description>My mum’s finally finished clearing out my grandparents’ house, and she’s brought back a few boxes of things: books, pieces of jewellery, notes. Nothing valuable, just mementoes. It was a long process, partly as they lived out in the western Highlands near Oban. But it got done eventually, after a lot of trips to the local dump and Oxfam. We accumulate so much stuff.
She had brought down a box of crockery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books I read last year</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/books-i-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/books-i-read/</guid>
      <description>I read less than I used to, and I forget most of what I read. A fact brought home to me last year when, bored at Christmas time, back at my parents’ house, I rifled through some shelves in my childhood bedroom, and pulled out a plain blue hardcover notebook.
I’d found an old reading journal, each line of the notebook had a ‘date begun’ and a ‘date finished’ for each book I read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think again about online friendships</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/think-again-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/think-again-online/</guid>
      <description>I go to a lot of marketing conferences. Which means I sit through an awful lot of marketing pitches and presentations. But, until last month, I hadn’t sat through a single one that made me reassess how I lived my life.
Becky Rowe, managing director at ESRO, a market research company, changed all this at Customers Exposed, an event organised by the Market Research Society. Her subject was one that plays out in the background of the minds of most people with an internet connection (that’ll be just under 3bn people): the nature and value of online friendships.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
