<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Advertising on Joseph Clift</title>
    <link>https://josephclift.com/tags/advertising/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Advertising on Joseph Clift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://josephclift.com/tags/advertising/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Not-so-hot coral</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/not-so-hot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/not-so-hot/</guid>
      <description>It’s always a pain when an ad isn’t worthy of what’s being advertised. Which is why seeing this spot from Monzo the other day felt like a particularly hard kick to the stomach.
Here’s why I’m about to be highly dramatic and over-critical about a tiny poster on a train. Monzo is the bank that has basically changed my life since switched my main current account there last year, due to its extreme convenience - all in the app!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The four types of agency-client relationships</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/four-types-of-agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/four-types-of-agency/</guid>
      <description>Agency/client relationships are getting ever more fraught these days: you only had to look at this week’s announcement from WPP that its sales are taking a big whack, and ominous signals from big advertisers like P&amp;amp;G that they wish to “reinvent” their agency relationships – which will, safe to say, involve paying them a lot less.
If such relationships are getting a bit abusive these days, then, Anselmo Ramos, founder of the WPP-owned, Ogilvy-affiliated agency DAVID, is here to help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 things I’ve learned about the Future of Strategy</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/5-things-ive-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/5-things-ive-learned/</guid>
      <description>Aside from my day-to-day tasks as a product manager, my big work project over the past year has been WARC’s new Future of Strategy report, which I conceived, researched and (finally) wrote. While it was a real passion project, it was also based on a big user need: the company’s hardcore fans are planners at ad and media agencies, yet within the marketing industry as a whole, the planning discipline is little-understood and often overlooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the purpose of brand purpose?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/whats-the-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/whats-the-purpose/</guid>
      <description>With so many heart-warming, CSR-led ads winning awards these days, setting a purpose seems to have become almost a prerequisite for launching a big brand campaign.
But many in adland would say these wins are due more to tugging on judges’ heartstrings rather than demonstrating great creativity or solid business results. Or even a sensible purpose in the first place!
This debate came into sharp focus at the Cannes Lions this year, according to a new analysis released by WARC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How marketers can make people focus</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/how-marketers-can/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/how-marketers-can/</guid>
      <description>Kudos to APG London for its new Thinking Around Corners series of events, one of which I attended the other week. The format’s simple, get three strategists in a room, and get their advice on cracking some challenging briefs.
The standout for me was a problem that’s always bedevilled advertisers with a message to get across: once you get people’s attention, how do you keep it?
How do you get people to concentrate on one thing for more than a minute?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kleenex, Apple, brand love</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/kleenex-apple-brandlove/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/kleenex-apple-brandlove/</guid>
      <description>It’s hard to work back from Apple to give brand advice to Kleenex…
So said Laurence Green, ex of the Cadbury’s Gorilla, and currently of creative agency 101 London, at an APG/Flamingo debate I attended the other day.
The debate was all about “brand love”. Specifically, about the kicking that controversial metric comes in for in ‘How Brands Grow‘. (More proof that, despite being published five years ago, Australian academic Byron Sharp’s magnum opus remains that rarest of things: a talked-about marketing book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Management and Leadership</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/management-and-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/management-and-leadership/</guid>
      <description>Management is doing things right; leadership is doing the right things.
– Peter F. Drucker</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas: British Adland’s Super Bowl</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/christmas-adland-superbowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/christmas-adland-superbowl/</guid>
      <description>Last month, I had the chance to interview planning superbrains Toby Harrison and Les Binet of adam&amp;amp;eveDDB.
That’s the agency responsible for Christmas ad hits from this subversive online-only spot for bag brand Mulberry…
To the ongoing series of sentimental, lushly-produced spots for John Lewis: a rare example of an ad that becomes part of the national conversation.
“It feels like Christmas advertising is where it’s hot now,” Binet said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kahneman, creativity and cocktails</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/kahneman-creativity-cocktails/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/kahneman-creativity-cocktails/</guid>
      <description>As part of a (very entertaining) talk at a Warc event earlier this week, Ogilvy vice-chairman (and ex-head of the IPA) Rory Sutherland argues that ad people have been exploring System One and System Two thinking for years: way before the terms were coined by Daniel Kahneman.
The man himself is obviously having a bit of a moment among adland in general, having been namechecked at basically every marketing event I&amp;rsquo;ve been to this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content and its discontents</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/content-discontents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/content-discontents/</guid>
      <description>The video above’s one I shot back in Cannes with Martin Weigel, head of planning at W+K Amsterdam. He’s talking about his beef with the word “content” (mainly definitional). I was reminded of it when, via Twitter, I stumbled across his blogpost on which marketing buzzwords he particularly dislikes, “content” among them.
Content. Also known as ‘branded content’. You mean spots? Oh, sorry, long spots. No? Oh, music videos? No?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the winner of the Warc 100</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/warc-100-winner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/warc-100-winner/</guid>
      <description>I helped launch the inaugural Warc 100 today. It&amp;rsquo;s a ranking of the world’s best campaigns based on their performance in effectiveness and strategy competitions over the past year. And our top-ranked campaign – and clear winner – was &amp;lsquo;Vodafone Fakka&amp;rsquo;, from JWT Cairo for Vodafone.
This campaign, which promoted micro recharge cards, used a cultural insight: in Egypt, shopkeepers often substitute small change for low-value items. So, they positioned the micro credit recharge card as &amp;lsquo;Fakka&amp;rsquo; – small change, handed out in place of these low-value items, and kept alongside the counter in shops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The story behind ‘Guilt Trips’</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing//writing/story-guilt-trips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing//writing/story-guilt-trips/</guid>
      <description>McCann took the Creative Effectiveness Grand Prix in Cannes this year with a campaign that tapped into a universal family dynamic: parents living in the sticks, children living in the city.
The big problem: how to get the kids to come and visit their parents more often. The big insight McCann had for their client, V/Line, a train operator based in Melbourne: why not aim the message at the parents, not the kids?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advertisements...</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/advertisements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/advertisements/</guid>
      <description>Advertisements are now so numerous that they are very negligently perused.”
Samuel Johnson, The Idler, 1759 (source)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advertising&#39;s economic impact</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/advertising-economic-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/advertising-economic-impact/</guid>
      <description>Following a winter of what seemed like unbroken rain, there&amp;rsquo;s been a hint of spring in the air these past couple of weeks here in the UK. And the nicer weather&amp;rsquo;s been matched by increased optimism among both British economic and advertising forecasters. Official predictions for 2014 UK GDP growth were revised up to +2.7% earlier this week, suggesting that the economy will at last regain its pre-financial crisis peak this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A pricing primer</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/a-pricing-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/a-pricing-primer/</guid>
      <description>Getting pricing right is a pretty fraught issue for brand owners. But what should the responsible marketer be doing to make things easier? The Psychology of Price, creative agency Draftfcb&amp;rsquo;s latest Breakfast Club event, held in London this morning, aimed to offer some answers. Behavioural economist Leigh Caldwell, author of a book of the same title as the briefing, and Draftfcb&amp;rsquo;s head of retail Niki Cook both offered their views – and both agreed that price-related decisions go a lot deeper than the actual costs of goods and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why all advertising theories are wrong</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/why-all-advertising/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/why-all-advertising/</guid>
      <description>There are many ways of defining advertising, but none of them really work on their own. That’s according to no less a source than planning legend Paul Feldwick.
Advertising’s biggest theorisers over history
Here’s why you should believe him. Feldwick – in his role at BMB (later bought by DDB), was responsible for iconic campaigns including the 1990s Barclaycard ads starring Rowan Atkinson. More recently, he’s become something of an industry guru, revered by many (sample ad blogpost title: “Is Paul Feldwick God?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing&#39;s Big Lie</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/marketings-big-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/marketings-big-lie/</guid>
      <description>Ever get suspicious that your Facebook friends are having too much fun? That the lives of people you follow on Instagram are too fabulous to be believed? According to Christophe Jouan, CEO of Future Foundation, all of this social media-based bragging should be a crucial concern for the marketing industry. Jouan talked to me about what he terms the Big Lie of marketing – also the title of a new book from Future Foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hover cars, branded content and Guanxi</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/hover-branded-guanxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/hover-branded-guanxi/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a star-studded day at the Cannes Lions International Festival of Creativity, with creative grandes dames Vivienne Westwood and Annie Leibowitz both sending the audience into a tweeting frenzy at the Palais des Festivals. (Westwood&amp;rsquo;s most-buzzed about quote, &amp;ldquo;if your ideas don&amp;rsquo;t make the world better - they are useless,&amp;rdquo; certainly chimes with a lot of the other Cannes conversation this week). But the prevailing theme for Tuesday was China: the world&amp;rsquo;s most populous nation and third-largest ad market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can ads do good?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/can-ads-do-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/can-ads-do-good/</guid>
      <description>Some may deride this idea as corporate greenwashing, but the idea of brands &amp;ldquo;doing good&amp;rdquo; as well as making a profit is becoming an increasingly hot topic. I was struck earlier this month at the World Federation of Advertisers (WFA) conference by client after client highlighting the need for brands to have a social &amp;ldquo;purpose&amp;rdquo;.
With that in mind, today&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;doing good makes for good advertising&amp;rdquo; panel at Advertising Week Europe was very much on trend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The art of the heart</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/art-of-heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/art-of-heart/</guid>
      <description>At TV Creativity: The Art of the Heart, an event held in London, Thinkbox, a UK commercial TV marketing body, offered some compelling statistics and research to highlight the potential benefits of the channel to advertisers.
But delegates were also offered some personal stories to go alongside the hard data, with three sets of ad professionals – planners, creatives and directors – offering a behind-the-scenes view on how some of the best TV ads of recent years got made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is advertising a science or an art?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/advertising-science-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/advertising-science-art/</guid>
      <description>Or, to put it another way, is advertising success achieved through incremental research, careful checking of data and sound planning – or is it more to do with the creative &amp;ldquo;eureka moment&amp;rdquo;? This &amp;ldquo;science vs art&amp;rdquo; question has troubled advertising&amp;rsquo;s biggest brains for decades. Remember that famous Bill Bernbach quote? &amp;ldquo;Advertising is fundamentally persuasion and persuasion happens to be not a science, but an art.&amp;rdquo;
The industry&amp;rsquo;s latest attempt at settling the matter came with a lively debate at the Edinburgh International Marketing Festival earlier this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad tips from Facebook and YouTube</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/ad-tips-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/ad-tips-facebook/</guid>
      <description>Facebook has had one of the roughest months in its short history since becoming a public company, with lowlights ranging from a 16% decline in its stock price to media complaints about Mark Zuckerberg&amp;rsquo;s restaurant tipping habits. And things seemed to be going from bad to worse at the Cannes Lions International Festival of Creativity yesterday when Paul Adams, the firm&amp;rsquo;s global head of brand design, disappeared backstage soon after starting his keynote due to what seemed to be a bad case of stagefright.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nadia Comaneci&#39;s Olympic campaign</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/nadia-comaneci-olympic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/nadia-comaneci-olympic/</guid>
      <description>Many attendees of the annual Cannes Lions International Festival of Creativity pride themselves on being forward thinking. But at this year&amp;rsquo;s event, a lot of minds will be focused on one future date in particular: 27 July 2012, when the summer Olympic Games begin in London. If you want to know why this is, follow the money.
The Olympics are a prime cause of the industry&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;quadrennial effect&amp;rdquo; – the lift given to global adspend every four years due to the happy convergence of major summer sporting events and the US presidential election.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The mathematics of creativity</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/mathematics-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/mathematics-creativity/</guid>
      <description>Robert Heath&amp;rsquo;s Low Involvement Processing Theory, the professional competency of chicken sexers and the box office success of the Police Academy sequels might seem unlikely source material for a single talk, but they nevertheless all made an appearance in John Leach&amp;rsquo;s presentation to the Account Planners Group (APG) in London yesterday evening. Leach – the self-described &amp;ldquo;Malcolm Gladwell with less hair&amp;rdquo; and planning director at PR group Bell Pottinger – used this source material to illustrate a single theme: the &amp;ldquo;mathematics of creativity&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are integrated campaigns effective?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/integrated-campaigns-effective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/integrated-campaigns-effective/</guid>
      <description>By common consensus, tightly integrated campaigns, broadcast across multiple media, are more effective than &amp;ldquo;non-integrated&amp;rdquo; campaigns, which either advertise on a single channel or take a laissez-faire approach to merging channels. But new research - commissioned by the IPA, based on analysis of 250 case studies from IPA Databank, and published in an upcoming book - challenges this point of view.
It seems that, on hard business metrics such as market share changes, loosely integrated campaigns actually perform better than campaigns that are integrated around a central communication idea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why brand relevance explains market movements</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/brand-relevance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/brand-relevance/</guid>
      <description>Some brands make it big; most do not. But why are certain brands successful in the first place? And why does a still-smaller group of brands remain popular over the long term?
In his 2010 book Brand Relevance: Making Competitors Irrelevant, US academic David A. Aaker attempts to answer these questions. He claims that &amp;ldquo;relevance&amp;rdquo; is a crucial factor in a brand attaining market leadership - and that companies become relevant by creating their own category or subcategory through innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why neuroscience?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/why-neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/why-neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Neuroscience is here to stay - and the insights it provides can be far more compelling than those from the traditional focus group.
That&amp;rsquo;s been the message from many researchers over recent years, as they use techniques from eye-tracking to FMRI to track the brain&amp;rsquo;s unconscious reactions to various stimuli. And it&amp;rsquo;s a message that was brought home once more by Gemma Calvert, founder of Neurosense, at a meeting of the Account Planners Group in London last night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emerging markets and listening brands: A perfect match?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/emerging-markets-listening/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/emerging-markets-listening/</guid>
      <description>Societies are always changing - and being able to predict accurately how societies will change in the years ahead is a matter of acute concern to advertisers. GfK Roper offered some forecasts of its own in its &amp;lsquo;The World to 2020&amp;rsquo; seminar, held in London this week, based on the years of data they&amp;rsquo;ve been gathering from over 30 countries in five continents.
In developed nations at least, people are now interacting with brands more directly than they did before, whether through saying they &amp;ldquo;like&amp;rdquo; it on Facebook, through leaving product reviews on Amazon or CNET, or through saving money by using mobile services like Voucher Cloud and shopping around for the best deal via price comparison websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-opportunity: Making a slightly better world</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/writing/co-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/writing/co-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>John Grant discussed the concept of Co-opportunity - also the title of his latest book, see Warc summary here - with a packed audience of planners at an APG event in London yesterday.
The rise of social media has led to a dramatic shift in power towards consumers and away from brands (and marketers). Grant, a co-founder of St Luke&amp;rsquo;s, sees this process as beneficial rather than destructive. He argues that co-operation can benefit both brands&amp;rsquo; bottom lines and society as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rise of the machines</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/rise-of-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/rise-of-machines/</guid>
      <description>Online display ads don&amp;rsquo;t tend to be a big part of the typical web user&amp;rsquo;s browsing experience. However, they&amp;rsquo;re a lot more important for media buyers and publishers - not least because, over recent years, the automated ad networks that have achieved primacy have driven down CPM rates across the board.
Representatives from both the buy side and the sell side discussed - and disagreed on - how the ads should be monetised, at an AOP event in London which I attended yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
