<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strategy on Joseph Clift</title>
    <link>https://josephclift.com/tags/strategy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Strategy on Joseph Clift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://josephclift.com/tags/strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Epic documentation</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/epic-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/epic-documentation/</guid>
      <description>It’s right there in the Agile Manifesto: today’s product teams should prioritise “working software over comprehensive documentation”.
A nice thought. But having notched up several years of working with Agile teams, I feel like these five words have led to an unfortunate belief taking hold among certain zealots: that we don’t need documentation at all!
Which is nonsense. We need the leanest, briefest, most maintainable documentation possible. But we need documentation all the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 things I’ve learned about the Future of Strategy</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/5-things-ive-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/5-things-ive-learned/</guid>
      <description>Aside from my day-to-day tasks as a product manager, my big work project over the past year has been WARC’s new Future of Strategy report, which I conceived, researched and (finally) wrote. While it was a real passion project, it was also based on a big user need: the company’s hardcore fans are planners at ad and media agencies, yet within the marketing industry as a whole, the planning discipline is little-understood and often overlooked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the purpose of brand purpose?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/whats-the-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/whats-the-purpose/</guid>
      <description>With so many heart-warming, CSR-led ads winning awards these days, setting a purpose seems to have become almost a prerequisite for launching a big brand campaign.
But many in adland would say these wins are due more to tugging on judges’ heartstrings rather than demonstrating great creativity or solid business results. Or even a sensible purpose in the first place!
This debate came into sharp focus at the Cannes Lions this year, according to a new analysis released by WARC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How marketers can make people focus</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/how-marketers-can/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/how-marketers-can/</guid>
      <description>Kudos to APG London for its new Thinking Around Corners series of events, one of which I attended the other week. The format’s simple, get three strategists in a room, and get their advice on cracking some challenging briefs.
The standout for me was a problem that’s always bedevilled advertisers with a message to get across: once you get people’s attention, how do you keep it?
How do you get people to concentrate on one thing for more than a minute?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content and its discontents</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/content-discontents/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/content-discontents/</guid>
      <description>The video above’s one I shot back in Cannes with Martin Weigel, head of planning at W+K Amsterdam. He’s talking about his beef with the word “content” (mainly definitional). I was reminded of it when, via Twitter, I stumbled across his blogpost on which marketing buzzwords he particularly dislikes, “content” among them.
Content. Also known as ‘branded content’. You mean spots? Oh, sorry, long spots. No? Oh, music videos? No?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet the winner of the Warc 100</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/warc-100-winner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/warc-100-winner/</guid>
      <description>I helped launch the inaugural Warc 100 today. It&amp;rsquo;s a ranking of the world’s best campaigns based on their performance in effectiveness and strategy competitions over the past year. And our top-ranked campaign – and clear winner – was &amp;lsquo;Vodafone Fakka&amp;rsquo;, from JWT Cairo for Vodafone.
This campaign, which promoted micro recharge cards, used a cultural insight: in Egypt, shopkeepers often substitute small change for low-value items. So, they positioned the micro credit recharge card as &amp;lsquo;Fakka&amp;rsquo; – small change, handed out in place of these low-value items, and kept alongside the counter in shops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why all advertising theories are wrong</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/why-all-advertising/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/why-all-advertising/</guid>
      <description>There are many ways of defining advertising, but none of them really work on their own. That’s according to no less a source than planning legend Paul Feldwick.
Advertising’s biggest theorisers over history
Here’s why you should believe him. Feldwick – in his role at BMB (later bought by DDB), was responsible for iconic campaigns including the 1990s Barclaycard ads starring Rowan Atkinson. More recently, he’s become something of an industry guru, revered by many (sample ad blogpost title: “Is Paul Feldwick God?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why neuroscience?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/why-neuroscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/why-neuroscience/</guid>
      <description>Neuroscience is here to stay - and the insights it provides can be far more compelling than those from the traditional focus group.
That&amp;rsquo;s been the message from many researchers over recent years, as they use techniques from eye-tracking to FMRI to track the brain&amp;rsquo;s unconscious reactions to various stimuli. And it&amp;rsquo;s a message that was brought home once more by Gemma Calvert, founder of Neurosense, at a meeting of the Account Planners Group in London last night.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
