<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Culture on Joseph Clift</title>
    <link>https://josephclift.com/tags/culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Culture on Joseph Clift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://josephclift.com/tags/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scream, Queen! It’s Freddy’s Revenge</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/scream-queen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/scream-queen/</guid>
      <description>I wrote the original version of this post for the Fringe! Queer Film Fest blog. I don’t trust them to pay their hosting bill, so I’m reposting it here.
I was a naive 8-year-old, sneakily watching taped-off-the-TV video nasties round my friend Paul’s house, in the far outskirts of London at the fag end of the 1980s. That’s when I first lost my mind to the Nightmare on Elm Street series - and its razor-fingered star, Freddy Krueger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are social media and gaming good for us?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/social-gaming-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/social-gaming-good/</guid>
      <description>One thing’s for sure: digital media has been blamed for a lot of society’s ills. And that’s despite its massive - and increasing - global popularity, with one piece of research showing that we touch our phones an average of 2,500 times daily, with 80% of our time spent on just five apps.
Two of digital&amp;rsquo;s most-popular by-products, social media and gaming, were put under the microscope by a series of speakers at Unfolded, an event organised by London-based creative agency Fold7 and held yesterday night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tapping the Kangaroo</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/tapping-the-kangaroo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/tapping-the-kangaroo/</guid>
      <description>Every day in London, thousands of fingers tap a cute Kangaroo logo on their smartphone screens. As a result, every lunchtime and supper time, thousands of young men have a job to do.
They’re participating in a new, digitally-enabled form of freelance labour: working for Deliveroo, the city’s number one takeaway app. Their job is to deliver food, on motorbikes and push bikes, toting huge, insulated square food-storage backpacks, branded with Deliveroo’s turquoise and black corporate colours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another London</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/another-london/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/another-london/</guid>
      <description>Another London: looking up Tottenham Court Road, 1974.
The city at its grimiest (and emptiest). Note the wonky railings and hump in the pavement on the near side, and the pedestrian crossing to nowhere on the other side. And the strip of single-story lean-tos, rapid rebuilds after the previous buildings were bombed out in the war; they lasted all the way to the mid-90s, apparently.
Another country: the &amp;ldquo;three-day week&amp;rdquo; and petrol rationing had bitten in earlier in the year; the Common Market referendum was a year away; the IMF bailout came in 1976.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The story behind ‘Guilt Trips’</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing//writing/story-guilt-trips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing//writing/story-guilt-trips/</guid>
      <description>McCann took the Creative Effectiveness Grand Prix in Cannes this year with a campaign that tapped into a universal family dynamic: parents living in the sticks, children living in the city.
The big problem: how to get the kids to come and visit their parents more often. The big insight McCann had for their client, V/Line, a train operator based in Melbourne: why not aim the message at the parents, not the kids?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
