<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Joseph Clift</title>
    <link>https://josephclift.com/tags/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Joseph Clift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://josephclift.com/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Waterfall or straw man?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/waterfall-strawman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/waterfall-strawman/</guid>
      <description>The whole Waterfall vs Agile comparison is a sham. It isn&amp;rsquo;t two competing ways of doing things. The Waterfall approach has never had serious support - not even from the inventor of the concept.
So many blogs, tweets and Medium posts about Agile have drawn the comparison over recent years. On one side, there&amp;rsquo;s the old bad Waterfall way of doing things - with bloated planning phases, long lead times, no user feedback, big releases, and no improvements to the initial delivery afterwards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSM1... and done</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/psm1-and-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/psm1-and-done/</guid>
      <description>So it’s done. After several weeks of reading a 19-page PDF file over and over, taking practice tests and reading countless blog posts, you can now, officially, call me master. Scrum Master. I got certified!
I’d have thought that would have come from the day job, where I work on two Scrum teams, but studying for the PSM1 Scrum Master certification actually underlined how little I knew about the guidelines of this process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>132 Days of Duolingo</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/132-days-of-duolingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/132-days-of-duolingo/</guid>
      <description>I spend around 10 minutes a day on Duolingo and I’m not convinced it’s worth it.
And the fact these doubts only started occurring to me after I completed a 100 day streak on this maddeningly well-designed and moreish app is… annoying.
Admittedly, 10 minutes a day isn’t a massive time commitment. But, over 100 days, that equals almost 17 hours. Most of a day! Is it even time well spent?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are social media and gaming good for us?</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/social-gaming-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/social-gaming-good/</guid>
      <description>One thing’s for sure: digital media has been blamed for a lot of society’s ills. And that’s despite its massive - and increasing - global popularity, with one piece of research showing that we touch our phones an average of 2,500 times daily, with 80% of our time spent on just five apps.
Two of digital&amp;rsquo;s most-popular by-products, social media and gaming, were put under the microscope by a series of speakers at Unfolded, an event organised by London-based creative agency Fold7 and held yesterday night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tapping the Kangaroo</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/tapping-the-kangaroo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/tapping-the-kangaroo/</guid>
      <description>Every day in London, thousands of fingers tap a cute Kangaroo logo on their smartphone screens. As a result, every lunchtime and supper time, thousands of young men have a job to do.
They’re participating in a new, digitally-enabled form of freelance labour: working for Deliveroo, the city’s number one takeaway app. Their job is to deliver food, on motorbikes and push bikes, toting huge, insulated square food-storage backpacks, branded with Deliveroo’s turquoise and black corporate colours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes we Kanban!</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/yes-we-kanban/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/yes-we-kanban/</guid>
      <description>Kanban is one of the most talked-about, but least-understood, ways we have of managing digital product development. At least, that’s the impression I got from a recent talk given by David Lowe, a Kanban expert and Scrum coach, at General Assembly in London.
A quick Google search suggests that Kanban has something to do with improving production processes in Japanese car factories. But a look around the blogosphere shows it’s since been sucked into the Agile/Scrum/Lean vortex that powers so much product discussion these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think again about online friendships</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/think-again-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/think-again-online/</guid>
      <description>I go to a lot of marketing conferences. Which means I sit through an awful lot of marketing pitches and presentations. But, until last month, I hadn’t sat through a single one that made me reassess how I lived my life.
Becky Rowe, managing director at ESRO, a market research company, changed all this at Customers Exposed, an event organised by the Market Research Society. Her subject was one that plays out in the background of the minds of most people with an internet connection (that’ll be just under 3bn people): the nature and value of online friendships.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rise of the machines</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/rise-of-machines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/rise-of-machines/</guid>
      <description>Online display ads don&amp;rsquo;t tend to be a big part of the typical web user&amp;rsquo;s browsing experience. However, they&amp;rsquo;re a lot more important for media buyers and publishers - not least because, over recent years, the automated ad networks that have achieved primacy have driven down CPM rates across the board.
Representatives from both the buy side and the sell side discussed - and disagreed on - how the ads should be monetised, at an AOP event in London which I attended yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
