<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recession on Joseph Clift</title>
    <link>https://josephclift.com/tags/recession/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recession on Joseph Clift</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://josephclift.com/tags/recession/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from a crisis</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/lessons-from-a-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/lessons-from-a-crisis/</guid>
      <description>“What we are seeing today is a backwash from what happened 10 years ago.”
So claimed former Chancellor of the Exchequer, Alistair Darling, in an event organised by the RSA and held in London a couple of months ago. Darling was in charge of the nation’s finances when the biggest financial crisis in a generation hit in 2007. He articulated a view that has been forming with the recent political ructions and rise of populism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Room 59</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/room-59/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/room-59/</guid>
      <description>Sunday family trips to the National Gallery in London are among my most-cherished childhood memories.
Up from our distant suburb beyond the edge of the District line, near Heathrow, being in town was a rare treat. The Gallery was free, and money was an issue for us. It was the 80s, early 90s at the latest, so the Trafalgar Square the Gallery faced was still pigeon-filled and traffic-clogged and grimy. It was wintry and raining outside, probably.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling the Pinch: An update on the UK consumer</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/feeling-pinch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/feeling-pinch/</guid>
      <description>In these times of economic volatility, rising unemployment and fears of a double-dip recession, gauging consumer attitudes towards financial matters has become ever more important to both governments and businesses. In the UK, The Futures Company has been conducting an ongoing research project on the topic since 2008, entitled Feeling the Pinch. And its latest results, discussed at a briefing in London earlier this week, make for pretty depressing reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So much for the recovery</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/so-much-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/so-much-recovery/</guid>
      <description>Eurozone bailouts, signs of a slowdown in China and - perhaps most worrying of all - uncertainty over the raising of the US debt ceiling have all hit the headlines recently. Shockingly poor US GDP data released last week have led some to suggest that the world&amp;rsquo;s largest economy could even be facing a double-dip recession. And, according to Warc&amp;rsquo;s latest International Ad Forecast - now available for subscribers to download - it seems that marketers are taking heed of all the bad news.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A report from Austerity Britain</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/report-austerity-britain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/report-austerity-britain/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s official: shopping at Aldi is now cool. According to new research from RAPP UK, unveiled at its Opportunity in Austerity briefing in London, cash-strapped Britons, faced with the economy&amp;rsquo;s stuttering recovery from its worst recession in decades, are making changes to their lifestyle - including doing more of their shopping at low-cost supermarkets.
After the bling-obsessed boom years, any taboo surrounding low-cost brands was blown away by the economic downturn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recession, responsibility and generational divides</title>
      <link>https://josephclift.com/writing/recession-responsibility-generational/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://josephclift.com/writing/recession-responsibility-generational/</guid>
      <description>Britain&amp;rsquo;s consumers are still suffering from the recession, despite the economy&amp;rsquo;s return to growth in late 2009. And new data from The Futures Company, presented at a briefing in London this morning, shows that people are being smart about adapting to this New Normal.
Savings rates have risen, debts are being paid down and the typical shopper is now more willing to compare prices to get the best deal and use discount vouchers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
